All right so I'm live I guess it's difficult to
compete with dinner but try to make it through here all right.
So, this talk is about developing three-d printing applications and
three print in general ...to remind you that there's a evaluation
form and we'd like to have you fill it out when the presentation is over.
With that I'd like to launch write-in start out with our agenda.
So, three printing...change quite a bit there's a lot of
opportunities that are presenting themselves at this time lot-of tools.
...were putting into windows ten we're going to go in-depth about the things that we're doing in windows ten that really
helped...developer and today we're going to announce and talk
...consortium...consortium is a group of companies have gotten together to
kinda help improve the file formats that we're going to be using for...printing in the future and then my
colleague emmett will be coming up and talking about three-and-a-half consortium in the future of three-d printing.
So, that let's launch right into it was really a revolution going on
and three printing it's really a great time to be in this
career.
Because three printing is kind of move from a very nation thing a very expensive
with making things too
much less expensive and works really well for doing short runs
and one offs I've been visiting a lot of companies I've seen a lot of what people are doing.
For instance I visited a company that was manufacturing for automotive
industry and they were making engine blocks of aluminum and they could turn
...four days and it was amazing
to see that because in the past.
Somebody would have to make a mold and then they would have to...the engine block the turn-around time for that was
about four months so as the iterated through the engine designs they found perhaps
some area was hot not getting enough cooling and...needed to modify the design they could get a very rapid
turn-around so it's interesting to think about now those were the engines that
were used in production those are...simply.
Prototype in testing.
three printing is doing today not just turning around the time it's allowing you to do
things that just could that possibly be done before?
I was handed a carburetor throttle body handed it to me
...I was shocked it...just a few ounces because the
entire inside of the structure was hollow and that's something you just can't do with traditional
manufacturing techniques so there is a revolution in the making and
I think it's going to be very interesting what's, what's happening somewhere break this down.
...sort of two-part because we have the desktop things that are going on and then we
have additive manufacturing which is going on in the industry so desktop printers
as you see here this is...qthree by three-d systems.
Hundred-thousand-dollars
the plastic is relatively inexpensive fifty bucks a kilogram.
It really opens up this is a this is a little bit more advanced printers that you scene because it has
...bed leveling...so, it's opening up three-d printing to
more people than just the people who do this for a hobby and they really they know
it inside and out and they want to learned its opening it up for
a much larger audience the education I was at high schools I'm working with kids doing
robots and suddenly you could see these kids visualize that they
can rapidly innovate their designed even though it's just a high school competition for
...they can rapidly innovate on their designs and they can see the
possibilities where they're going with this they can print the pieces that it
takes to build a robot and it's really interesting to see that there's a whole new generation of people coming up
that are going to think very differently about how you do product design.
Three-d print bureaus...we...manufacturing facilities
enables those that don't have printers.
Those people who don't want to flats with the printers the ability to print
from their desktop and receive something much more complex so the print
...of the fabrication services they could do very high-quality parts they
can get down to fifty microns precision they can do things
that have strength better than casting and you could do...many
materials which suddenly takes the this whole concept all great what am I going to do with this
plastic single color thing it really opens up a lot of possibilities
specifically for developers who are developing apps.
That might be that customize existing things.
So, let's take a look at the opportunities for the developers so.
There's lots and lots of things that I've seen out there everything from.
I want to phone case and that phone case I want customize I want my logo
...I want my name on it I want my sport on it my nickname.
These things are very easy content to print and very easy to modify
and customized for individuals so there's entire industry springing up around
I'm going to print you are case that service specific material and that's customized in
a specific way that you want to see it and you could do this very interactively over the internet
scented in haven't manufactured by some third-party and deliver it
...opening up a lot of opportunities for developers to move into
right now so the key is to find the content define
...and maybe not try to
boil the entire ocean around three-d printing but to
incentivizing designers to leverage the content that's out there to create
specialize things for your customers and individualized things.
For your customers.
So, let's be clear about three bring.
Three printing is not always so easy.
In the past.
You had non-standard driver stacks you've had a
different slices that you could choose from you had com ports you have to configure
of open-source software that you have to put together and work through and
that's not always so easy for my mother to do so.
We need to really overcome some of these problems printers have a fairly
low success rate like if you can get fifty percent success really get what you're looking for
...could do a pretty good and that's not really analogous to what you think of in
the normal printing.
It's a little bit lower success
rate so we have a ways to go in order to get these desktop printers really,
really working the other thing is.
Nobody can tell
what the printers do you can't get any information from your printer in terms of
...the materials
even on paper printers you could tell what kind of paper uses but in a three-d printer
today you really have no information about what's coming back with the materials which the
thin wall size what's the what's the bed size the volume of the bed
so this is really been blockers to entry in the past.
So, what I want to do is I want to talk about?
What we've done in...ten?
That would help solve some of these problems.
...start out with this first bullet workflow.
This is an interesting concept we call it workflow but I really need to clarify exactly
...the process of actually getting your print prepared to go to the printer.
So, if you keep this context throughout the rest of this presentation will be a little more clear what I'm talking
about so repair capabilities and api is
repair we call repair many other people call it healing or
...fixing but what we call repair is fixing a
models so that it can be prepared to print a model could be filled with holes if you had
a for instance and animation program and
that animation program had a bunch of cartoon characters and it doesn't have to be
a solid model it can be a facade they could be just a you know,
texture on top of a shape and if you go to try to print something like that
it just doesn't work when you print something has to be a solid object so this
is been a major blocker as the industry is developed is
getting it printable so we're putting api is in the box that are going to do this for
you also another major driver is plug-and-play.
If you don't have plug-and-play and you have to do a bunch of configuration especially around
com ports to get things lined up all of the proper things
installed for your workflow to go through it really becomes problematic my
mother is not going to do it...mom wants to do is plug-in and just have
at work I want to do file print so this whole abstraction that we have around
two-d printing we really need to extend that
into three printing and then finally.
...a lot of people just won't do won't have these printers but maybe they want play
with it or experiment with it and try it so cloud printing we feel is very important printers
are expensive still and the quality of the print the difficulty it is to
manage the print really lends itself for people saying,
yeah, I want to make this part I needed
customize part but I really need in metal and I'm not going to go spin three hundred-thousand-dollars
...a laser centered printer just so I can do this
one print so cloud printing we think is very important part or strategy.
Remember...printing about twenty years ago.
...special driver for lotus one-two-three
for a specific printer so you go to buy software...the first
...do is check and see if you've got the right printer that they have a driver supported for
it was ridiculous microsoft solve that problem this is where we are right
now with three-d printing is we need to understand
what materials how it's, you know, and, each just work everything needs to be
...from the repair tools to the slice or everything needs to work in a
role when you plug it in so that it's a file print experience.
So, we're going to talk about three workflow once again let me go back to remind you that the workflows the
process from file print to actually the printing starting.
Okay, so, the file print experience is very familiar dialogue everybody uses it in
tutti printing and it's a very good
analogue applying here you can select...three printer or you can...cloud printer.
Unfortunately with three-d print.
It's a much more complex process to get through that
it is with tutti print.
So, there's options for the prayer which is the same
as a tutti there's material assignment which is kind of analogous to
selecting right paper to print on but you also have to be
able to look at your objects and did put them on the plate so that they print
...the right place there's a lot of different things to do so?
I'd like to do a demo.
Of windows ten three-d workflow.
Start by hitting the right button...I hope.
Tyra okay this is any app I
...three-d builders our app but you could think of this is being in the app
at all so I'm going to start this is a touch app or a mouse app either
one you wish so I'm going to start by just
saying print because the app really isn't so important as the print workflow.
here's the workflow notice my train my...multiple objects on the bed.
There's a few key things you get an error right in the top that saying you're not on the
bed this print is not going to succeed because you're not on the
bed an easy way to do is just a click it and it goes on the bed
okay I have another error up...I'm going to talk about that later.
So, I would like to look at this object first so I'd like to spin it around like this and take a
look at it and, yeah, it looks pretty good that's what I want to see upside down
right side up one of the key things is there's a true
experience with the volume of the print and so.
Perhaps I would like to
...model and make it bigger...therefore more expensive
or smaller and I can do that I could do it to the point where it no longer fits
of my print bed so I can scale it back down again.
So, that's important it's important
because of cost if you're going to send this out to a print bureau the bulk of the
price's based upon the volume so if you print if you go
...scandals and you get scanned and
zoom yourself up really big you probably going to pay a thousand-dollars to get your little scan
printed at the print bureau so you might want to scale it down a little bit to be a little more affordable you can...down to the twenty
five-dollar range but since it's volume goes up as a...of the size.
Okay.
Other thing is if I happen to I can move things around on the print bit to make
of fit if I happen to have them up off the printed when they,
come on,...that's unfortunate I would really like to lay it down on
different bid so you could just pop it right down to the print bed so that you're
not printing supports up to your object which is floating mid-air so other things.
There are some editing tools that we've left in here.
The next thing that you need to do is you really need to...what material is an since we have the api
is in the operating system that the workflow has the ability to understand the printer bed size
...the materials I can select this guy and I can say I really want to have a
blue train.
And, then I can go to the selection tool and select all
...select the train and say I want my wheels green.
Okay,...we think of color as a material is a property
of a material but you could just as well be saying I want this
golda aluminum or whatever and then when you send it out to print it
prints and then finally over here on the left-hand side you can see you could selected density...this
information is coming back from the printer is what is the density that should be printed in the density of the
end fill the quality whether be draft quality or high-quality
and whether you want rafts or supports on if the printer had more capabilities you
would have more capabilities listed there and then finally when everything's done
...are gone you just hit print and off you go and you...
...you go and print.
Ok, so, that's a little demo of the direction we're heading.
Windows ten in windows eight we barely tolerated the printing and
...windows ten we've really fleshed it out to give people control so that's
are really cool but what does that mean to you as a
developer what that means is we've done
the heavy lifting you don't have to do a three-d viewing tool.
You don't have to create the user interaction in order to view things and spend things around and
look at it if you're very simple...and you really just want to.
Print something like I have a cartoon here I like to print you know, joe the guns
...you really just need to throw that model over the wall
to us through the file print capability and then let us take
care of the rest of it we can repair it we can scale it for printing and we can
...materials to be printed or the colors to be printed and then you can move on to either printed
a print bureau or printed locally so the three-d content is all you
have to do simplifies ux you get
...focus on your core features will take care the heavy lifting around the print pipelined.
But, what if you want to do something a little more complex than that?
For instance if you might be aac had application that you really want to have a great deal of
control over what you're doing maybe you don't want to just throw it over to our repair tool because
repair does change the model and if your...you're probably very concerned about tolerances...the
model being which uone we're actually giving a set of api...talked in the workflow.
About the api
is the api to get information about the printer what kind of material can handle
...capability we don't have all of the printer capabilities put into windows ten
yet but we certainly know the volume and we know the materials loaded in the printer so you can go through
do that selection but if you're more like a cat application and you really want to do the
...the selection of the materials as a designer and then
send those materials down we give you the api to do that understand you
can install your printer or you can stop printer meta data and you could actually do that
Selection from your
cat application when it gets to the print workflow will get out of the way...see
others already printers there's already material selected will back off if you if
you're designer selects something less complex...that's not a
printer material you can edit by making selections in the print workflow.
We also are putting in the box validate...tools because.
One of the big problems is the models aren't
printable so it really is best for an advanced
application something that's not printing toys or something that you don't care so much
about your shapes being modified sometimes these are just tenths of a
millimeter to close holes and sometimes they're bigger like if you did a plane cut
...you left the bottom of...model from a scanned completely open we would have to close that.
Look, we're going to put the api is in-box to do that automatically so that
you could access those api or you could access other api is right there to get it fixed and will
automatically fix it and will also send you back information about
what we've changed this is a single highest barrier?
Removed.
Cloud printing services you can really make some fantastic things with the
...printing services so there's
a large companies who are actually putting desktop printers on the deaths of their
designers and engineers and those large companies will.
Print something in plastic.
And, they'll see that they fit and all,
you know, drive fitted in the assembly and make sure that's right but ultimately they want something better cloud
printing services enables so we partner with cuba phi.
which is three-d systems and these are some of the things that they have available
straighter file print you can get professional materials
professionally done and if you look at some of these things these things are not
easy to do using traditional manufacturing that can methods?
Driver development.
We have.
To driver models.
...very briefly because probably not so many of you guys are
doing driver development we have a standard inbox driver it works with a
...marlon based printer that except g code.
With this standard model you don't have to
...the box and it comes for windows update and all you need to do is
set the usb descriptors there's two things you set the first one is the microsoft so
the tell it it's a three-d printer and the second one is you pick a matching
...best matches your printer like if it's a delta you might pretty delta if it's a
cartesian you could pick that so we have a number of standard models that you
...you say I'm like that but my bed sizes different
and here's my bed size so no driver development necessary you want to build
a represent or you can have a driver the
just works with windows automatically.
The other one is a virtual software...so what we've done
is in order to make the driver developments simpler.
We've made a driver
...software driver and we put a little layer of a deal on the bottom
dls something that you would do and what it does is it takes information from the
software driver allows you to decide what topology want to use how to
communicate with your printer and if you need to make any transforms like perhaps
you have something unique about your printer where you need something that you have to transform like you're
sending blocks of decode instead of individual...something like that so there's,
there's three parts of it you can add a custom slice or through a capability we
color render filter?
You can...a custom interface to the dl.
You can also replace the workflow another workflow I showed you in windows is
completely replaceable you could make but, windows device application
that does anything specific to your printer and as soon as
you're printer drivers installed to back off completely and we'll
...is you drop down the printer selection the workflow will disappear
and your workflow will appear there so all three of those pieces make it very
customizable for your printer you don't have to be decode you can have your own slice or if you think that's
part of your ip...works.
Because of these two driver models you can go out there and you
can see on the table today.
Are seven printers out there those are just the ones we have out there but
and these are a number of...printers...and all of them we
...very recently...be creative so we have a number of printers
the just work windows plug-and-play and everything's included?
So, working with three-d data.
This is sort of the end of my part of the presentation but what you see here
in this chair is a very complex.
Print.
So,...is here to talk about three mf format
in the future design of where we're headed
with three printing in the future so here's an?
Thank you so first off who am I well I haven't actually
...microsoft for that long I originally got...three-d printing as a hobby
is I've got in by making open-source designs if you
wandered around in the three-d printing world you might have run across a few the things I've made you can find my things
on thing averse but in the process of doing design for three-d objects I
realized just how limited we were in the software just how many problems
they were actually making things work making things get printed properly and,
just in creating the things that you can imagine and,
I was kind of excited to come to microsoft because there was
an opportunity to actually fix a lot of these problems that I saw in
the world we role dealing with one of the big ones, you know,
there's a lot of
complaints out there about the file formats that we currently use and,
we're trying to address that by actually making a new format now you've got to have
a good reason to make a new format right I mean nobody wants extra format
...for the fun of it but at the end of the day there is a good reason here and the
reason is that the really hasn't been something truly for three-d printing
before the closest thing we had were a couple of formats a
enough and...a...I'm sure well-known...most view and,
it's deficiencies are well-known as well it's lacking all kinds of features it's
close to thirty-years-old now it simply doesn't have the kind of data that we need.
...math has also tried to kind of address this but they've...a different approach and,
you know, basically what happened was we were approached by a
...various partners from the three-d printer companies and cad companies and they told
us look neither of these formats is solving our problem we
can't adoptees we need something better and here are requirements
he said all right we're in a good position we're in a place where we can talk to everybody in the industry
...a place where we can help to define good agreement and find some is actually going to
work actually going to solve the problems and the feasible so,
you know, there are lots of other formats...at as well obviously.
Manufacturing is not limited to three-d printing and the rest of the manufacturing world mostly uses
...they've got file formats...stepper very common but,
these are nerves formats and let me tell you non-uniform rational
busy spines are not for everyone they're very powerful but they're also very complicated
...beard entry and there's a reason
is only a few giant cad companies that really push this kind of stuff because they have the
enormous investment and expertise to do that but, we're looking at is trying to broaden this out
to wider set of developers and that means using something simpler and
more easily implement...now a lot of what's been using the three-d printing industry
is actually sort of re purpose rendering formats things like lbj
vr eml there's many more the problem with these format is they're really not targeted
at three printing so they've got all kinds of great information about moonlighting and
fog in whatever you might need for rendering but that doesn't matter to us we care
about is material and materials a lot more than color we're talking about metals
we're talking about strength we're talking about conductivity all sorts of things that
just have no meaning in a rendering world and in addition a lot of rendered
objects simply aren't real.
They're meant to look all right but fundamentally...smoke and mirrors they're not solid and they're
not something that any printer can create something out of that's something that we really need to look at
when we're doing our format that's truly for three-d printing.
So, what we've done is we've assembled a consortium
because at the end of the day nobody cares reduce alone we need to work with
partners the whole point of this is to get broad adoption that's the only way that
a format is useful to the world so we've partnered
up we've got leading partners in the cad space for talking to, you know, does and auto
desk net fab does cad work as well or talking to middleware companies
that deal with reading models for print and for ...putting together
for instance the workflows to make manufacturing possible as places like shape
ways and net fab and we're also...partners in manufacturing so as I
am solutions makes metal printers hp is getting into the printing industry now
audio desk makes their own and, the important thing of having all these people involved
as we make sure that we can actually have something
that addresses everybody's needs and works for the whole pipeline all the way from
cad to manufacturing without needing any sort of?
Re translation or disruption of the data.
Of course was really important that this been open format
I mean realistically the format is only worth something to all
of these partners if it's broadly adopted has absolutely no reason for
to be proprietary so you can go out online right now to our website
...dot io and you can find...specks.
we are working to make sure that this is available to everyone and to help adoption
...actually opening up some open-source code so you will I don't know if
...actually live just yet but there will be links to get have repositories that have
code under open-source...licenses and this is to help with file parsing
with read and write at the end of the day there's no reason to ask everyone of you developers to go read
our spec and go independently write a parser that's a waste of time so
we'll dual once will do it...
we'll make it available and this is a good way to make sure that we have a format that's consistent
that actually gets the data read properly and every place and we
understand that this is how we can make something that's actually useful for the industry.
Now when we go through creating...of course we're looking at the other formats
are saying well I've talked about the deficiencies so how are we going to fix that why is
three-month going to be different well we basically have to take all the good
parts of the other formats remove all the bad parts and our own things we think
are truly unique and really important for three-d printing so first and foremost needs
to be complete you can't have external references floating around
that get broken every time you move a file this is something that I've dealt with too many times to
count we use a common method open packaging conventions that basically
allow us to have a package that contains any number of files we need has clear
relationships...ways to basically keep all of the data organized and, finally,
you know, we also need to be contact so this is a zip package that helps to make sure that the
transfer is fast
efficient but internally we also have to avoid duplications we use we make
a strong use of references make sure that are vertices are not repeated we reference them
are objects are not repeated we can make multiple copies and reference these
things are really important for keeping the file size reasonable keeping the parsing speed up?
then we also decided it was important at the end of the day this be human readable format looking
...what formats of really been adopted well this turns out to be important I mean,
you know, is developers that you need the ability to actually go through and
error check and debug and dealing with a giant binary blob is
a huge problem by using xml internally we make this format
largely self documenting you can read through it you can see what somebody meant and,
we have lots of tools available to deal with this kind of thing it's a very
well-understood standard we will make use of binary formats when that makes sense but we'll
use well-known ones things like p energies and jpeg that store data
and very well-known ways because certainly there are times
...ridge data where you don't want to just write everything out in english?
But, there are some other important x...considerations here as well.
The extensibility this format is really key.
We made the core specification as minimal as we could.
So, basically this is sort of as...they can do all of the most
basic things that basic printers need and basic...apps use and you don't have to think
about any of the more complex stuff you have a very narrow set of things that you
need to implement and it's a short spec it's an easy read
...promise helped write it and, then we need to make
extensible because even though we know a lot of the features we need now
we can't possibly know all the future features will need in the future so we actually make use
of xml namespaces to have a really clear extension model so you can have a new names
...for your extensions and you can make it clear the beginning of file hey I've got
this extra information and you can as an app make it clear whether you
understand better not and if you don't understand those if you have
an implemented those kinds of extensions you can just wipe them out ignore them you have to
do any extra processing you can just drop down to the minimal core...or
whichever said of extensions you do understand without actually losing the ability to process the
file we already have created one extension we called the materials and properties extension you can
...our website and that's to handle all these things like color when you're looking at things
you'd expect from a rendell format especially when you're talking about sending things to a print bureau
they can do full color this allows us to have things like vertex
...texture maps material definitions
even composite materials all the things that you would expect and need and
they're in clear ways that we can easily transfer from existing
file formats into this one without losing information maybe the most
important thing that separates this file format from others is that it is
...ambiguous?
And, this is really the key that separates us from the file
formats of come before specially these rendering formats.
To be a true three-d printable file you
half to be solid.
You have to actually represent a volume and this is
a mathematical concept and it is not a simple one and it's been
a big difficulty because the words like manifold...oriented and
water tighter thrown around all the time but they're actually rather poorly defined if you put
poke into them you'll notice that in different places they use different definitions depending on what
their actual application is we've gone through and looked at the three-d printing application
and found very specific definitions that we know will work for this
swedes clearly defined in the spec it's clear how to verify it
this is again part of our will be in, you know,
open-source code to make sure that anyone can verify
...method verify consistently and then of course knowing using
that connecting back to for instance the windows api or we can now repair of file and
...that if you had a problem coming in maybe it was from, you
know, of rendered objects that was not in fact closed we
can guarantee you a manifold output will really print solid.
So, you know, the other part of this is what about self intersections
this is fundamentally ambiguous you can have an object that
intersect itself and there's not really a good way to
...a lot of times is actually very common coming out of design apps and the
question is well ok so now what's the inside and what's the outside when we actually again have
a very specific rule that's easy to handle in processing that
allows you to remove all ambiguity from that so even if you have a self intersected file, you know,
that any printer will choose the same way to represent that
as a solid object.
That's all well and good but most of that is things that...have existed,
you know, I mean fundamentally this is a triangle mesh format we've seen
this before it's nothing crazy it's nothing out-of-the-ordinary we're just
...nailing down those specific things that
help to make sure that it's really going to work reliably for three printing.
But, what's really interesting to me
at least is that we can do something much more exciting in the future.
What's amazing about three-d printing is you can now fabricate things that simply were not fabricate
...before.
You can look at pictures like this we can build the micro structures we can build,
you know, these tiny little detailed pieces halloween out
objects making more efficient structures there's printers
they can do material gradients you can actually continuously
changing material like the mixture of alloy or the mixture of a composite across
apart so suddenly you don't have these sudden juncture is where you go from
stiffed...flexible and, have your part tend to break there no now you can you
can smoothly transition that across well we've never been able to do that before
and what this means is that we've also never been able to design is before
because what's the point of designing a part that's not possible to make?
We have all kinds of amazing casual that exist but they're actually not made for this
kind of thing so we now have this huge opportunity
for the developers to think about what can we do to enable designers to take
advantage of what three-d printers can now do we need tools that simplify
this immense complexity we need ways to actually take,
you know, inspirations from nature for instance where.
You have these
incredibly complicated designs things that are fractal in nature but
...that way because they are optimized they are the best shape for the
problem there solving we can take advantage of that in our engineering designs as well and
...product design is to make things were beautiful you can look at generate of
design where this whole new paradigms possible where instead of saying I'm going to design this by
...michael uppers and measuring and making it just this shape you can step back and say
well wait really I'm trying to solve a problem here I'm trying to hold up this
weight I'm trying to resist this kind of motion maybe I can
represent something like that and actually have algorithms
and computers design the part that does that well...
to my constraints and can create these incredibly complicated object without my having
to specifically please every facet that's why there's so much possibility here
you look at nature for an example and you can see that
...solving problems that we need to solve...engineering to their finding things that have
incredible strength to weight ratios by removing material they have
...surface area of volume ratios if they're trying to create
reactions and such and they do this through find micro structuring and problem,
you know, methods that might seem random at first but in
...very highly optimized and solve the problem exceedingly well?
We really don't have tools right now to do this effectively these are the kinds of tools that we need to
create.
And, when you look at this...in this really funny position
where the hardware has actually exceeded the software which I mean seems
crazy right I mean software developers l moore's law whatever we can we can be everybody right but,
hardware suddenly coming along and say hey complexity is free?
We can build as complex...
is you want and the only prices the volume of material that you've put into the print will
sadly that's not true for us computation is not free.
Developing algorithms is not free.
And,...to the point now where even though the printers can print these incredible things we don't
even know-how to make them we don't even know what a transfer the data I've talked to designers who
are on the leading edge of this stuff and they're creating files in traditional formats that are
terabites and that's just not feasible we have to do better so
that's where we're going with three mf we know that we need to fix this problem
on interchange level to allow...developers to fix this on
a design level so we're working on new methods of
organizing data that are actually unique stuff that's truly new truly different
so, we can actually represent micro structures
...efficient way so we can do this stuff and actually create.
New methods to look at data and in so doing
create new ways of actually operating on that data more efficiently.
I'm really excited to be working on this and I hope you'll stay tuned for the stuff that we
haven't in-store I can't really...yet because it's not ready we have to prove that
...works we have to make some software that actually proves that are designs are
good they'll really do what we can that...claim they'll be able to and then we will
release details to you we've got the consortium all agreed.
Hand the nice thing about this...ecosystem with all these companies involved is
that now you...to worry you've got one format all the way down the pipeline from
design to print you never have to worry about loss of information you can close
the design loop you can take that file that
was just printed and that's ready to go right back into
...design program you haven't lost anything if you need to change something
it's there you don't have to run back up the pipeline and try to find the original designer and,
that's really important is right now that's a big problem and finally just having an industry
back consortium is really important because it means that there's a lot
of these implementations that are already existing or in progress by these companies to support three-m
...and it's not limited to membership in the consortium
...we'll invite other people to...members as theycome and ask us
but more importantly doesn't matter you can anyone can use three
mf consortium is more about driving the standard and all of that.
But, fundamentally this is a format for everyone to use that's why it's open.
So, you know, finally czar called action, you know, if
...and app developer we've talked about all these three-d print api
...ten that-you can call to easily do file print allow your users
to target not only their own local printers but also the cloud printing services so,
we'll be putting those up...msdn soon.
For the hardware manufacturers we've got a three
print driver sdk we're going to be updating that with all the latest stuff that you've seen in the presentation that
will be available online as well standard driver description such will also come up on msdn
shortly and finally for everyone at all...the spectrum if you're processing three-d content
...encourage you to take a look at our three...core and extensions specifications
...three-and-a-half dot io website.
you'll be able to find all the information you need and of course contact us if you have questions.
So, finally.
Evaluate the session please if you know,
we'd love to hear your feedback about what we've done.
And, that's all I've got so does anybody have any questions.
Anonymous been pretty clear present
...gallon on working on scanning technologies to make sure that scale
...that comes through scanning...
Yeah, so, as you can actually see at...booth we
areworking three-d scanning we've got the connect vtwo we showcased of connect
fusion...through our app three-d builder which is free and we just made that so that
it would be easy for people to use a three-d scanner
...course we can then create three-m...up in full color you can send them up
the pipeline to get printed in full color by
the cloud service so we're really excited about three-d scanning but of course you can...much more than
just the connect and, it will be exciting to get more of those pipelines coming in?
Hello, network,... I'm a student I'm in college now and I'm
...software on the acting mechanical engineer for a project...project and
one of the big pinpointed printing that I have is clearances and tolerances so I
...malay wants to be happen into comes out either point for a four-point-five
too and I tried it with...I put a...through a screw through it doesn't work.
Is that it could be fixed in software?
Yeah, that is in fact that's one of the key things that were that were putting into the
material spec it is not in the windows ten materials back but it's not just about
the material that part is probably shrinkage so some of
the material shrink that they suddenly don't work they don't fit anymore especially with
like abs plastic so one of the materials that we're talking about putting in the materials
...working with the print companies is what's the shrinkage so you could build
...too big so that when it shrinks
...to the right size as far as being too big I
wrote caused that that's a little interesting probably just...printers off but shrinkage and thin
wall ...was spacing all of these capabilities were trying to
...industry together so that the printers can actually
described them especially the professional printers can describe exactly what their capabilities are
what we need to do to compensate for a variations like that, yeah,
obviously...love the printer drivers themselves to be able to understand this and compensate on their own
and I'm sure they'll be moving in that direction but part of the reason
that we make these print capabilities available to apps is that if you want a very powerful app
they can get you the absolute best results on certain kinds of
printers you'll be able to pull those capabilities out and do operations
that you understand as the app developer will actually increase the quality of the final product?
we have an application that...st old data I'm sure you recommend that we replace that with the
three mf yes they're format but with will be any standard tools
or windows support for doing conversion from...three-man so the way we look at
it actually is from...api perspective we simplify it by just basically
say you can put in a vertex a triangle...something more generic more
like your internal representation of the data and,
that can be packaged automatically by the api...mf and,
that way we worry more about the actual data representation that you're
using in your program rather than going from one on-disk format to another.
Okay, well, if there's no more questions certainly appreciate you coming please fill out your survey and.
See on the three-and-a-half website.
Thank you.